-你是B队  -雾气升起 通讯中断
- You Bravo? - Fog came in, comms went down.
继电器干扰
Interference from the relay.
前情提要
星盟已经在那儿了
The Covenant was already there,
在将圣所玻璃化之前就在了
on Sanctuary before they glassed it.
佩雷斯
Perez.
如果计划是将星球玻璃化 何必要先入侵呢
If your plan is to glass a planet, why invade it first?
这人谁啊
Who the hell is this guy?
艾克森先生是来接替哈尔西博士工作的
Mr. Ackerson is Dr. Halsey's replacement.
你认为他们要干什么
What do you think they were after?
我认为他们在为了更大的目的训练
I think they were training for something bigger.
他让我们护送一个技术团队执行什么修复任务
He's got us escorting a tech team on some fix-it mission.
-他让你们去修什么   -某个不知名的星系的
- What's he got you fixing? - Comms relay went down
-通讯中继站失灵了  -那为什么派钴队去呢
- in some nowhere system. - So why send Cobalt team?
告诉他们会遇到什么就行 告诉钴队
Just tell 'em what they're walking into. Tell Cobalt.
约翰 我从来都不赞成哈尔西的方法
John, I never approved of Halsey's methods.
-那个科塔娜系统  -不
- The Cortana system-- - No.
-从来就没打算  -你把她取出来了
- Was never intended-- - You took her out.
我不会授权银队
I cannot authorize Silver Team
执行战斗任务
to perform combat operations.
你应该和我待在一起的
You should have stayed with me.
作为庇护的交换
In exchange for asylum,
这些人要履行契约服务
these persons submit to indentured service.
我不知道怎么会这样
I don't know how it happened,
但其他家族 他们并不怕你
but the other families, they're not afraid of you.
我有你想要的东西
I have something you want!
悬赏 凯瑟琳·哈尔西的位置
A bounty, for Catherine Halsey.
我知道她在哪儿
I know where she is.
心宿二 你他妈干嘛呢
Antares, what the hell are you doing?
索伦066 你被捕了
Soren-066? You're under arrest.
怪物唯一想让你
The only thing the monster wants
知道的是
is for you to know
你爱的所有一切
that there's nothing you can ever love
它都可以夺走
that it can't take away.
你现在信我了吗
You believe me now, don't you?
下午好
Good afternoon.
两块抹茶饼干 两份澳洲坚果 两个酥饼
Two matcha tea cookies, two macadamia nut, two shortbread--
还有一杯蓝油桃茶
And a blue nectarine tea.
我的最爱
It's my favorite.
是不是很美
Isn't it beautiful?
地球上独有
It's native only to Earth.
七个月后 橙色的花朵
In seven months, the orange flowers
会变成红色的大果实
are supposed to turn into big red fruits,
咬上一囗
and then when you take a bite,
种子会在你嘴里爆开
the seeds just pop, pop, pop in your mouth
就像装满果汁的小气球
like little balloons filled with juice.
我还拿了这个
I also have this.
这应该是某种游戏
I think it's some kind of game.
你已经有一个了
Oh, you already have one.
没关系
That's all right.
-你能教我吗  -可以
- Will you teach me? - Yes.
但首先我希望你能帮我做件事
But first I'd like you to do something for me.
没问题
Of course.
我想你告诉我 你离开这里后会发生什么
I want you to tell me what happens when you leave here.
有问题吗
Is that a problem?
我 我不知道能不能说
I... I don't know if I'm allowed to say.
我肯定没关系的
Oh, I'm sure it's all right.
还有另一个房间
There's another room.
-什么样的房间  -一个大房间
- What kind of room? - A big one.
我不知道你会怎么叫它
I dunno what you'd call it.
这个是干什么的
What does this one do?
这样玩家就能对结果下赌注了
That allows the players to bet on the outcome.
然后呢
And then what happens?
掷骰子看谁先来吗
We roll to see goes first?
不是 房间外面是什么
No, what's beyond the room?
有条走廊
Oh, um, there's a hallway.
-继续  -有很多扇门
- Go on. - There are many doors.
门后是什么
What's behind the doors?
我不
I don't...
我不能看
I'm not supposed to look.
谁不让你看的
Who told you not to look?
一个男人 我来掷
The man. I'll roll.
讲讲这个人
Tell me about him.
你会喜欢他的 他人很好
You'd like him, he's very nice.
他就是一直送你礼物的人
He's the one who's been sending you all the gifts.
跟我讲讲这个男人
I need you to tell me about the man.
-我鼻子流血了  -我知道
- My nose is bleeding. - I know.
告诉我他长什么样
Tell me what he looks like.
我不舒服
I don't feel very good.
告诉我他叫什么
Tell me his name.
-我好怕  -我知道
- I'm scared. - I know.
这个男人 他叫什么
The man, his name.
他的名字
His name!
告诉我他的名字
Tell me his name.
-你干什么呢  -训练
- What are you doing? - Training.
你听到士官长说的了
You heard what Chief said.
你还要这样多久
How much longer are you gonna keep this up?
他们说我可以执行任务了
They said I'm good to go.
你可以去找艾克森谈谈 花点时间
Well, you could talk to Ackerson, take some time,
-找个机会  -时间 干什么
- get a chance to-- - Time, for what?
治疗
To heal.
大多数时候我都不会注意到
I don't even notice it most days.
我们都清楚才不是这样
Well, we both know that's not true.
我是斯巴达战士 凯
I'm a Spartan, Kai.
是要去打仗的
We're at war.
你可以把你植入物放回去
You can put your pellet back in.
有助于缓解疼痛
It will help with the pain.
那他们得先朝我开一枪
They'll have to put a bullet in me first.
你打算盯那个东西看多久
How long are you planning on staring at that thing?
艾克森觉得我有问题
Ackerson thinks there's something wrong with me.
我从没想过自己会想念哈尔西
I never thought I'd miss Halsey.
感觉他们不信任我们
It's like they don't trust us.
咋了
Do you?
我怎么了
Do I what?
觉得有什么不对劲吗
Think there's something wrong?
他们把科塔娜从你
It's only been six months since...
脑袋里才取出来六个月
since they took Cortana out of your head.
-不是这事  -那是什么事
- It's not that. - Then what is it?
我了解你 约翰
I know you, John.
-我们不只是  -我看到她了
- We're more than just-- - I saw her.
谁 你看到谁了
Who, you saw who?
马吉 在圣所看到了
Makee, on Sanctuary.
-马吉死了  -我知道
- Makee's dead. - I know.
-我亲手杀的她  -我知道
- I shot her myself. - I know that.
好吧
Okay.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
-什么  -待命
- What? -"Standby."
为什么要换
Why did you change that?
我觉得意思是
Uh, well, I think it means that--
他们还在外面呢 还没回来呢
They're still out there. They haven't come back yet.
-你知道的对吧  -钴队呢
- You know that, right? - Where's Cobalt?
-我只是做本职工作而已  -出什么事了
- Look, I'm just doing my job. - What's going on?
是 我们也想知道呢
Yeah, that's what we're trying to figure out.
钴队出什么事了
What happened to Cobalt?
不清楚 他们告诉我
I have no idea. They tell me
来把牌子换了 所以我就过来换了
to change the board, so I, I change the board.
谁让你来换的 凯斯 艾克森
Who tells you to change it? Keyes, Ackerson?
换回去
Put that back.
下一个
Next.
克莱夫 我们找到一个
Clive, we've got one.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
拜托
Ah, come on.
那个可不属于你
That doesn't belong to you.
但你属于我
But you belong to me.
你跟斯皮夫签过契约
You're indentured to the Spiffs.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
你的标签可不是这么写的
Well, your tag says otherwise.
嘿 站住
Hey, stop!
放下枪
Drop the gun!
去小巷
Take the alley!
站住 她在这
Stop, she's here!
她在这
She's here!
让开
Move!
她在那边 垃圾处理器 追
She's there. The disposal! Move!
闭嘴 听到没
Shut up. Did you hear that?
去那边
Take that side.
牲口
Animals.
放聪明点
Be a smart girl.
鲁比·安买下了索伦的船员 他不会回来了
Ruby Ann bought Soren's crew. he's not coming back.
克莱夫
Clive?
你个狡猾的贱人
You slippery bitch.
真可惜 现在我都不想速战速决了
That's a shame. Now I won't even make it quick.
停
Stop.
我说了停
I said stop.
有多严重
How bad is it?
没事
It's nothing.
你们这帮混蛋
You assholes.
一辈子都在打仗
At war your whole life,
崩溃的时候会意想不到的
surprised when you break down.
-让我帮你  -这里不行
- Let me help. - Not here.
我可以建议他们把你从前线撤下来
I could recommend that they pull your ass off the line.
我也可以杀了你
And I could kill you.
这才对嘛
There she is.
放松 没人在看
Relax, no one's looking.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
-疼吗  -不疼
- That hurt? - No.
混蛋
Dick!
-和气些  -别让他们看到
- Be nice. - Don't let them see.
没事 有我在呢
It's cool, I got you.
谢了
Thanks.
你知道自己不可能一辈子都这样的
You know you can't do this forever.
斯巴达克战士永不死
Spartans never die.
我认真的
I'm serious.
还有其他事可以做
There's other things to be,
其他生活方式
other ways to live.
你有考虑过这些吗
You ever think about that?
考虑什么
Think about what?
不做斯巴达战士的人生
Life without all this Spartan shit.
你是说活的庸庸碌碌
You mean a life that doesn't matter?
路易斯 抱歉 我不是
Louis, I'm sorry, I didn't--
-没事  -我不是说
- It's all right. - I didn't mean...
我知道你们这帮混蛋怎么想的
I know how you assholes think.
我曾经也是你
I was you once.
你以前很优秀
You were great.
曾经是最优秀的
You were the best.
别拍马屁了
Don't blow smoke up my ass.
但这还真是实话
But it's true.
真希望你能跟我们一起作战
I wish you were out there with us.
是 我以前也这么希望过
Yeah, I used to wish that too.
怎么就改想法了
What changed?
你不会理解的
You wouldn't understand.
钴队在哪儿
Where's Cobalt?
要喝一杯吗
Do you want a drink?
我不喝酒
I don't drink.
当然
No, of course not.
那食物呢 你吃东西吗
What about food? Do you eat?
钴队出什么事了
What happened to Cobalt?
他们还活着吗
Are they still alive?
据我所知 斯巴达战士是不会死的
Well, as far as I know, Spartans never die.
派我们出任务 要不然我就去找能派我们出去的人
Clear us for action, or I'll find somebody who will.
你是在威胁我要越级行事吗 约翰
Are you threatening to go over my head, John?
你喜欢等级制度 我尊重这点
You like a hierarchy, I respect that.
但别搞错了 约翰
But make no mistake here, John.
海军情报局才是主脑
The ONI is running the show.
而我就是海军情报局
And I am the ONI.
你确定不需要些什么吗
You sure I can't get you something, hm?
那我就直说了
Then allow me to be direct.
你对圣所事件的描述已被证实是可疑的
Your account of events on Sanctuary has proven dubious.
什么
What?
我们无法证实其真实性
We were unable to corroborate it.
去找那个下士 佩雷斯谈啊 她当时也在场
Well, talk to that corporal, Perez, she was there.
我谈过 我们谈了很久
Yes, I did. We spoke at length,
但你坚持发生的这些事
but these things that you insist happened,
星盟精英消灭了陆战队
Covenant Elites wiping out Marines?
那些陆战队员死了
Those Marines are dead.
你认为他们是怎么死的
What do you think happened to them?
我认为是星盟将星球玻璃化导致
I think the Covenant glassed the planet.
我认为这是场可怕的悲剧
I think it was a terrible tragedy.
但事实是 那位下士
But the fact remains, the corporal
并没有证实你的说法
did not confirm your story.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是她完全不记得
It means she has absolutely no recollection
你在圣所遇到的那些事
of what you say you encountered on Sanctuary.
不可能
That's impossible.
她在撒谎
She's lying.
你设身处地为我想一下 约翰
Put yourself in my position, John.
鉴于你最近的行为 你会相信你吗
Given your recent behavior, would you trust you?
没有我们就赢不了这场战争 长官
Can't win this war without us, sir.
你说得对
You're right.
我需要个士官长 我们都需要
I need Master Chief. We all do.
但约翰 说到底
But John, at the end of the day...
这身衣服换谁穿都行
he's just a guy in a suit.
我给你带了吃的
I brought you food.
怎么了
What's wrong?
拉埃拉 你下来干什么
Laera, what are you doing down here?
我跟你说了船准备好我会去找你
I told you I'd come get you when the ship was ready.
你说今天就能准备好
You said it would be ready today.
是 我知道我说了什么
Yeah, I know what I said.
我们发现个问题
Um... we found a problem.
我们在流体系统管道中发现了个裂缝
We found a crack in the stream manifold.
-要多久  -那艘货船周围有很多碎片
- How long? - There's a lot of debris around that cargo ship,
受到的撞击比我们预想的要多
took more hits than we realized.
-多久  -很难讲
- How long? - It's hard to say.
几天吧 也许更久
A couple of days, maybe more.
我们尽力了
We're doing the best we can here.
你应该上楼休息一下
You should go upstairs and get some rest.
索伦绝不会丢下你们任何一个人
Soren never would've left any of you behind.
那艘货船处于衰变轨道
That cargo ship was in a decaying orbit.
我们被击中 失去了陀螺仪 要么分离 要么
We got hit, lost the gyro. It was either detach or--
你说过了
You said that.
-凯斯勒怎么样  -凯斯勒很好
- How's Kessler doing? - Kessler's fine.
这种事对于孩子来说很难
This sort of thing's pretty hard on a kid.
-索伦没死  -当然没有
- Soren is not dead. - No, of course not.
他还活着 明白吗
He's alive, do you understand me?
明白
Yes.
拉埃拉 我们都想找到索伦
Laera, we all wanna find Soren.
你要知道这不是碎石星唯一一艘飞船
You know this isn't the only ship on the Rubble.
这是索伦的飞船
This is Soren's ship!
你们的舰长
Your captain.
等一下
Wait.
你耳朵怎么回事
What happened to your ear?
我是做错事了吗
Did I do something wrong?
关
Kwan?
不是 大人事小孩不懂
No, it's grown-up stuff.
大人事我懂的
I know grown-up stuff.
-我得离开  -为什么
- I have to go. - Why?
因为 就是得走
Because... I just do.
坏人在找你
Bad people are looking for you?
你怎么
How do you--
我都说了大人的事我懂的
I told you I know grown-up things.
-你什么都不知道  -你有危险
- You don't know anything. - You're in danger.
你 你妈
You, your mom--
等我爸回来 他就会保护我们
When my dad comes back, he'll protect us.
他回不来了
He's not coming back!
凯斯勒
Kessler.
-里兹 我看到你了  -靠
Riz, I see you. - Shit!
太慢了
Too slow.
已确认目标身份 准备开火
I have PID on target, taking the shot.
士官长
Chief!
游戏结束
Game over.
跟我说说 是什么感觉
Tell me, what is it like?
-什么  -输的感觉 我不知道
- What? - Losing, I wouldn't know.
-你真烦人  -因为我没输过
- You're insufferable. - Because I've never lost.
-是 知道了  -所以对我来说
- Yeah, I get it. - So for me,
这是个全新的体验
it'll be a new experience.
-士官长 让他闭嘴吧  -再来
- Chief, make him stop. - We're going again.
-里兹 你上  -收到
- Riz, you're up. - Copy.
-我可以继续 士官长  -我说了里兹来
- Well, I can go, Chief. - I said Riz.
-士官长  -干嘛
- Chief! - What?
瞧瞧她
Look at her.
嘿 还好吗
Hey, you good?
很好 士官长
Yes, Master Chief.
有什么想说的吗
Something you wanna say?
来吧
Come on.
-瓦纳克  -我来搞定
- Vannak. - I got her.
已确认目标身份
I have PID on target.
加油 加油啊
Come on, come on.
里兹
Riz!
起来
Get up.
-不许放弃  -士官长
- Don't you quit. - Chief.
-起来  -我做不到
- Get up! - I can't.
别再逼她了
You've gotta stop pushing her,
我们在这训练一晚上了 为什么
we've been out here all night training, why?
因为他们在训练
Because they're training!
我跟你说过我在圣所看到了什么
I told you what I saw on Sanctuary.
我们的敌人就在那里
Our enemy is out there.
他们越来越近了 我可以证明
They're getting close, I can prove it.
你打算怎么证明
How are you gonna do that?
我要去找钴队
I'm gonna find Cobalt.
再一次
Run it again.
再来
Again.
游戏结束了
The game's over.
但我们要玩到50分
But we're playing to 50.
我已经50多分了
I got over 50.
每轮骰子我都翻倍
I turned the doubling cube each round,
你每次都接受了
and you accepted every time.
有时候吃点小亏
Sometimes taking a small loss
比试图获胜要好
is better than trying to win.
明白了
I understand.
派你来的那个男人是谁
Who's the man who sent you here?
你怎么知道他的
How do you know about him?
这些可爱的礼物
Well, these lovely gifts.
肯定是有人给你的
Someone must be giving them to you.
流个不停呢
It won't stop.
跟我说说那个男的
Tell me about the man.
他是
He's...
是 你说过他人很好
Yes, you said he's nice.
是 但描述一下他
Yes, but describe him.
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
你要死了
You're dying.
什么 我是做错什么了吗
What? Did I do something wrong?
看我 看我
Look at me, look at me.
-我好怕  -我知道
- I'm scared. - I know.
-我好害怕  -告诉我他叫什么
- I'm very scared. - Tell me his name.
告诉我那个男人 他的名字
Tell me the man, his name.
这有什么意义呢
What's the point in this?
里兹 放松 没事的
Riz, relax. You're good.
我不该来这里
I shouldn't be here.
他是唯一一个能帮到你的人
He's the only guy that can help you.
你怎么知道
How would you know that?
因为他救过我
'Cause he's the one who saved me.
听着 我们从增强手术中出来的时候
Look, when we came outta augmentation...
我觉得自己焕然一新
I felt completely new.
即使有人开始生病
Even when people started getting sick,
我也是不可战胜的
I was invincible.
几天后
After a couple of days,
我视野边缘出现一片黑暗
there was this darkness at the edge of my vision.
我假装它不存在
I just pretended like it wasn't there.
但它蔓延
But it grew...
越来越大
and it grew.
我谁都没告诉
I never told anybody.
你本可以告诉我的
You could have told me.
-不行  -为什么不行
- No, I couldn't. - Why not?
因为那样你就会知道我不是你们中的一员
'Cause then you'd know I wasn't one of you.
我知道自己只有几天时间
I knew I only had a few days.
我不想当个瞎子
I didn't wanna be somebody going blind.
我想当斯巴达战士
I wanted to be a Spartan.
哪怕只那么一小会儿
Even if just for a little while.
我能看到东西的最后一天
You know, the last day I could really see anything...
我记得看着你们所有人
I remember looking at all of you...
是如此的骄傲
how proud you were...
如此的美丽
how beautiful.
然后一切陷入黑暗
Then it all went dark.
保重
Be well.
这位是
Who's this?
一个朋友
She's a friend.
你好啊 朋友
Hello, friend.
我有点担心约翰
I am a bit worried about John.
不是士官长的能力 而是这个人市身
Not Master Chief, but John the man.
我知道你们共事很久
And I know how long you've been together.
知道你在乎他
I know you care about him.
事实上 我敢说
In fact, I venture to say
你可能比任何人都了解他
you probably know him better than anyone.
-同意吗  -我
- Do you agree? - Well, I--
我想也许你能帮我
I thought perhaps you might help me
帮帮他
to help him.
你能做到吗
Is that something you could do?
当然
Of course.
你有没有看到过任何行为迹象表明
Have you witnessed any behavior
约翰可能会对他的团队构成威胁
that might indicate John could be a threat to his team...
甚至可能对自己构成威胁
or, God forbid, to himself?
没有 长官
No, sir.
那我就放心了
That's a relief.
我只是觉得太多了 长官
I just think it's a lot, sir.
承载他所承载的 目睹他所目睹的
Carrying everything he carries, seeing everything he's seen.
就像他们对他做的那样 长官
Like what they did to him, sir.
我只是有时候在想
I just wonder sometimes...
他能不能让过去成为过去
if he can let the past become the past.
你担心约翰的精神状态吗
Do you have concerns about John's mental state?
不 绝对不是 长官
No. Absolutely not, sir.
士官长很可靠 他是最好的
The chief is solid. He's the best we've got.
我相当理解他看上你什么了
Well, I certainly understand what he sees in you.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
只希望他重视你的忠诚
I only hope he values your loyalty.
就这些了吧
Will that be all?
是的 解散
Yes, dismissed.
我的门永远为你敞开 凯
My door is always open, Kai.
你为什么不告诉艾克森你看到了什么
Why didn't you tell Ackerson what you saw?
抱歉 现在没空
I'm sorry, this isn't a good time.
不
No.
祖母 回屋里去 好吗
Abuela, just go back inside, okay?
大家都在等你呢
Everybody's waiting.
-这是谁啊  -他就要走了
He was just about to leave.
你很大只嘛
You are very large.
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
他是我同事
He's someone I work with.
你跟塔莉亚都在那个星球上吗
You were there on that planet with Talia?
是的
Yes.
那还站外面干嘛
Why are you standing out here?
进来一起呀
Come and join us,
我们在屋顶上准备了一大堆吃的
we have a table full of food up on the roof.
你不是第一个来看我的
You're not the first to come see me.
你们这些战士以为伤疤只存在于外部
You warriors think your scars are on the outside,
但其实不是
but they're not.
那是什么
What is that?
不过是你的伤痛
That's just your pain.
没关系的
It's okay.
让它走吧
Let it go.
你的人生是你的
Your life is yours.
是属于你的
It belongs to you.
我向你保证
I promise you,
是你的
it's yours.
瞧瞧
A ver,
招呼客人吃东西啊
make sure our guest gets enough to eat.
你俩是什么情况
What's the story with you two? Hmm? Hmm?
能安静吃饭吗 拜托了
Can we just eat, please?
瞧瞧这哥们
Look at this guy,
肯定特别招女人喜欢
he must have women climbing all over him.
也能是某些男人的菜哦
Probably some men too.
嘿 管好你自己
Hey, mind your business.
拜托 塔莉亚以前没带过人回家
Come on, Talia never brought anyone home before.
他不是我带回来的
I didn't bring him home.
是 我觉得我们都应该知道他们有没有
Yeah, and I think we all deserve to know if they're...
安东尼奥
Antonio?
够了 安东尼奥
Basta, Antonio.
不好意思
Sorry.
嘿 你的KDR是多少
Hey, what's your KDR?
击毙和被击毙率
Kill-Death ratio.
不是吧兄弟 你不玩斯巴达进攻的吗
Come on, man, you don't play Spartan Attack?
我不记分的
I don't keep score.
我差点吓尿裤子
Think I almost peed myself.
都跟你说了 他就是其中一员
I told you, he's one of them!
我打给贝托
Oh! I'm calling Beto.
-不行  -是 该打
- No. - Yeah, you should.
怎么了 家里有斯巴达战士来吃饭哎
What? We have a Spartan at our table.
当然得打给他了
Of course I'm gonna call him.
我想致敬酒词
I'd like to make a toast.
敬塔莉亚和她的陆战队
To Talia and her Marines,
还有斯巴达战士
and the Spartans.
感谢他们的牺牲
We thank God for their sacrifices.
敬塔莉亚
To Talia.
-干杯  -塔莉亚
- Salud. - Talia.
小表妹狠狠教训了那帮星盟垃圾
Little cousin who kicked some serious Covenant ass.
嘿 你怎么了
Hey, what's your problem?
干得漂亮 混蛋
Way to go, asshole.
我干什么了
What did I do?
中继站附近通讯中断
The comms went down around the relay.
我不知道是什么原因造成的
I couldn't figure out what was causing it.
我当时在扫描波段 然后
I was scanning the band and...
就听到了
I heard something...
干扰里有声音
in the interference.
你听到什么了
What did you hear?
不知道
I don't know.
我只知道还有别人
I just knew we weren't alone.
我知道外面有东西
I knew there was something out there.
我能感觉到
I could feel it,
兰德也能感觉到
and Rand could feel it.
我什么都看不到
And I didn't see anything.
现在我战友都牺牲了
And now all my guys are gone.
你怎么解释
How do you explain that?
你怎么解释为什么那东西没杀我
How do you explain why that thing didn't kill me?
因为它本该也把我杀了的啊
'Cause it should've killed me.
这就是我没告诉艾克森的原因
That's why I didn't tell Ackerson.
他们授予我勋章
They gave me a medal.
我还是不知道由头是什么
I still don't know what it's for.
因为活下来吗
Surviving?
我只是活下来了而已
Is that all I did?
不是
No.
你听到了一条信息 这种情况还会再次发生
You heard a message. This will happen again.
你每天都会想起这事
You'll think about it every day.
他们的脸会在你最意想不到的时候蹦出来
Their faces pop up when you least expect.
不会好转
Doesn't get better.
只会渐行渐远
Just gets further away.
真奇怪
It is strange.
克隆人都说是个很好的男人
The clones all described a nice man.
可你却站在这里
And yet here you are.
我们都清楚终有一天我会来
Well, we both knew I'd be here someday.
我父亲在弗农港的花园里有棵
There was a pomegranate tree in my father's garden
石榴树
in Port Vernon.
他花了数年时间培育它
He spent years cultivating it,
尽管那棵树并不是安迪密安星球的本土植物
even though they're not native to Endymion.
他曾经每天都在日出前几小时
And he used to wake me up a couple of hours
叫醒我去打理花园
before sunrise every day to till the garden.
我为此怨恨过他 觉得这份工作有失我身份
I resented him for this, I thought the work was beneath me.
我记得有天晚上 有场雷雨
And I remember one evening there was a lightning storm,
我偷溜出房间 把他的树点着了
and I snuck out of my room, and I set his tree on fire.
他从没怀疑过我跟这件事有关系
He never suspected I had anything to do with it.
我从没告诉过任何人这个故事
I have never told anyone that story...
然而不知怎么的 那棵树
and yet somehow that tree...
只有一个人知道这件事
There's only one person who could know about it.
我向你保证 如有雷同纯属巧合
I assure you, any resemblance is pure coincidence.
她在哪儿
Where is she?
-科塔娜吗 她很安全  -约翰在哪儿
- Cortana? She's secure. - Where's John?
先不要操之过急
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
你想从我这里得到什么
What is it you want from me?
我想给你介绍个人
What I want is to introduce you to someone.
这位是朱莉娅
This is Julia.
她将是你的随从
She'll be your attendant.
我相信你们二位会很高兴认识对方的
I'm sure you two will enjoy getting to know each other.
你的树
Your tree.
给我看钴队任务的飞行计划
Show me the flight plan for Cobalt team's mission.
没有与该呼号相关的任务
No missions associated with that call sign.
给我看所有斯巴达的飞行计划
Show me all Spartan flight plans.
显示斯巴达飞行计划
Displaying Spartan flight plans.
你好 科塔娜
Hello, Cortana.
你好 艾克森上校
Hello, Colonel Ackerson.
我为你提供的信息有用吗
Did you find the information I provided useful?
相当有用 谢谢
Quite, thank you.
关于哈尔西博士 你还有什么
Is there anything else you would like to know
想了解的吗
about Dr. Halsey?
没了 可以以后再说
No, we can save that for later.
我给你的问题有什么进展吗
So, have you made any progress with the problem I gave you?
有的 但这个模拟很复杂
Yes, but it's a complex simulation.
如果你能让我访问外部系统
I could provide you with a more accurate analysis
我能给你更准确的分析
if you could give me access to external systems.
恐怕不行
Well, I'm afraid I can't do that.
但你尽最大努力
- Oh. - But give it your best shot,
即使有误差裕度
even with a margin for error,
你的预测还是有价值的
there's value to your projections.
根据我掌握的数据
Based on the data available to me,
可能性为97%
there's a 97% probability.
根据你所得到的数据
And with the data you've been given,
有没有什么可行的策略
are there any viable strategies you would recommend
可以防止这种结果
to prevent that outcome?
不管采取什么行动
All of my simulations return the same result
我所有模拟结果都是一样的
regardless of any action taken.
我明白了
I see.
所以没什么可做的了
So there's nothing to be done.
我可以继续模拟
I can continue to run simulations.
不必了
No, that won't be necessary.
你要走了吗
Are you leaving already?
对
Yeah.
我会尽可能再来看你的
I'll try and visit again.
你不会的
But you won't.
你没办法来
You can't.
根据模拟结果
According to the simulations.
我知道
I know.
只是人类会这么说
It's just something people say.
交叉搜索通讯中继站
Crosscheck communications relays.
有两个正在执行的任务
There are two active missions.
子午线中继站 标准船员轮换
Meridian relay, standard crew rotation.
未知任务   埃里丹星系
Unknown mission, Epsilon Eridane system.
放大
Zoom in.
任务时间 81小时
Mission time, 81 hours.
-识别呼号  -无呼号
- Identify call sign. - No call sign
与此飞行计划关联
associated with this flight plan.
他们就没离开过那个星球
They never left the planet.
HV32 这里是致远星飞行B队
Hotel Victor 3-2, this is Reach Flight Bravo.
你被批准进入长角牛空域 航向249
You are cleared for Sector Longhorn, heading 2-4-9'er.
收到 B队 32退出
Copy that, Bravo. 3-2 out.
自动驾驶解除 新航线
Autopilot disengaged, new course.
-不是训练吗  -怎么回事
- No training? - What's going on?
我们不是要去长角牛谷吗
I thought we were going to Longhorn Valley.
我还挺期待把你们打的落花流水的呢
I was looking forward to turning you all into chump bait.
-计划有变  -什么
- Change of plans. - What?
-我们要去哪儿  -韦谢格勒中继站 里兹
- Where are we going? - Visegrad Relay. Riz.
就在星盟发动攻击之前
The comms array on Sanctuary went down
圣所的通讯中继器失灵
just before the Covenant attacked.
韦谢格勒几天前断联 他们派钴队去了
Visegrad went down a few days ago, and they sent Cobalt.
我们去把他们找回来
We're going to get 'em back.
所以我们可以作战了
So we're cleared for combat?
是的 小维 准备好
Affirmative. Vic, ready.
瓦纳克 搭建主要通信接囗
Vannak, conduct PCIs.
好的 士官长
You got it, Chief.
任务具体内容是什么
What exactly is the mission?
在致远星的星盟
The Covenant's on Reach.
扛住
Halt!
准备好
Make ready.
天
Jesus.
稳住
Steady.
停火 停火
Cease fire! Cease fire!
停火
Cease fire!
靠
Oh, shit.
一队
First squad.
放松
Easy.
一队 报告情况
First squad, sit-rep!
二队 出发
Second squad, go!
交火
Covenant!
够了
Enough!
这场战斗不公平
There's no honor in this fight.
门.
Door.
麻烦了
Please.